JOE BOCOCK

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Nottingham United Kingdom

EMAIL

joebocock@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

GitHub

Codepen

Personal Site

SKILLS

PHP

Laravel

JavaScript

MySQL

AWS

Docker

React

Vue

Next.js

Redis

Git

Mentoring

Linux

PROFILE

Passionate Software Engineer with over 7 years of experience in developing web-based applications, designing APIs, and managing projects alongside both small and large teams. Skilled at building event-driven systems and specialising in improving developer experience. I create tools that enable developers to write the best code without any obstructions.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Backend Software Engineer, Paddle

Aug 2022 — Present

- Worked within a tight-knit team of 5 to deliver a world class developer experience, both for external and internal developers.
- Designed and built a high-throughput webhook delivery service by leveraging Laravel and event bridge.
- Helped external developers slash integration times by producing simple yet powerful SDKs for multiple languages like Node and PHP.

Senior Software Engineer, Accu

Apr 2021 — Aug 2022

- Methodically refactored a PHP legacy monolith code-base while still frequently delivering new features.
- Innovated in front-end user experiences and interactive sales information for a leading manufacturing and components provider using React, Tailwind and Alpine.
- Managed expectations of both internal and external feature requests while solving existing platform issues by integrating new technology like Algolia, Lambda and Docker.

Software Developer, SUMS

Sep 2018 — Feb 2021

- Integrated new payment processing methods into existing architecture with providers such as Stripe and Sage Pay (Opayo).
- Migrated older technology such as jQuery or Codelgniter to fresher frameworks like React and Laravel.
- Crafted high-quality code and furthered my understanding of database technologies with software like MySQL and PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Diploma in IT & Communication, Lincoln College

Jan 2016 — Dec 2017

Diploma in Engineering Technology, Lincoln College

Dec 2017 — Aug 2018